This is the belief state space for the sensorless vacuum problem.
这是无传感器真空问题的信度状态空间
So we started off here.
我们先从这里开始
We drew the circle around this belief state,
我们在这个信度状态画个圈
so we don't know anything about where we are.
所以我们对所处的位置一无所知
But the amazing thing is if we execute actions,
但是奇怪的是 如果我们执行动作
we can gain knowledge about the world even without sensing.
即使没有感知到任何东西 我们可以获得对世界的了解
So let's say we move right.
那么我们向右移动
Then we'll know we're in the right-hand location.
然后我们知道了右侧的地点
Either we were in the left and we moved right and arrived there,
我们位于左侧 向右移动到达那儿
or we were in the right to begin with and we bumped against the wall and stayed there.
或者起初位于右侧 翻过墙来到那儿
So now we end up in this state.
现在我们最终达到这个状态
We now know more about the world.
现在我们想对世界了解更多
We're down to four possibilities rather than eight,
我们只剩下四种可能性 而不是八种
even though we haven't observed anything.
即使我们没有观察到什么事情
And now, note something interesting,
现在注意到一些有趣的事情
that in the real world,
在现实世界中
the operations of going left and going right are inverses of each other,
向左和向右移动的动作都是反方向的
but in the belief state world,
但是在信念状态世界中
going right and going left are not inverses.
向左和向右移动并不是反方向的
If we go right and then we go left,
如果我们向右走 实际上是向左走
we don't end up back where we were in a state of total uncertainty.
我们不会出现在完全不确定的状态
Rather, going left takes us over here,
另外 向左走会使我们到这儿
where we still know we're in one of four states rather than in one of eight states.
我们还知道还处于四个状态之一 而不是八个状态之一
Note that is possible to form a plan that
注意可能会形成一个计划
reaches a goal without ever observing the world.
不需要观察世界就可以达到目标
Plans like that are called conformant plans.
这样的计划称为一致性规划
For example, if the goal is to be in a clean location,
例如如果目标是到达干净地点
all we have to do is suck.
那我们要做的就是吸取垃圾
So we go from one of these eight states to one of these four states,
我们从八种状态之一转向四种状态之一
and in every one of those four,
在四种状态中
we're in a clean location.
我们处于干净的地点
We don't know which of the four we're in,
我们不知道处于四个中哪个地点
but we know we've achieved the goal.
但是直到我们达到了目标
It's also possible to arrive at a completely known state.
也可能达到完全已知的状态
For example, we start here.
例如我们从这里开始
We go left. We suck up the dirt there.
向左走 吸取那里的垃圾
We go right and suck up the dirt.
向右走 吸取垃圾
Now we're down to a belief state consisting of one single state,
现在我们剩下只包含一个单独状态的信念状态
that is we know exactly where we are.
即我们准确知道了我们的位置
Here's a question for you.
这里有个问题
How do I get from the state where I know
我如何从只知道目前方块
my current square is clean but know nothing else,
而不知道其他的状态
to the belief state where I know that I'm in
转变为知道右侧地点
the right-hand-side location and that that location is clean?
且右侧地点为干净的信念状态？
What I want you to do is click on the sequence of actions - left,
我希望你选择行动的顺序
right, or stuck - that will take us from that start to that goal.
左 右 或停住 够让我们从初始位置到达目标